buyingiq.com 2014-06-30

# Privacy Policy | BuyingIQ

At BuyingIQ.com ("BuyingIQ" or "us" or "we" or "Website"), we want the user ("your" or "you") to know exactly how and when we collect and use information that can specifically identify you, such as your name, mailing address, phone number, and email address ("personal information"). This privacy policy applies to your use of BuyingIQ and doesn;t apply to any third party linked to us. If you do not agree to this use, please do not use the Website or any of the Services offered on or through the Website.  
Note: Our privacy policy is subject to change at any time without notice. To make sure you are aware of any changes, please review this policy periodically. 

### COLLECTION AND USE OF INFORMATION

BuyingIQ.com does not require that you provide, nor does it collect, any personal information if you are just browsing the Website. We may offer you on the Website non-transactional and transaction based services ("Service(s)") in which, subject to applicable terms and availability, you may participate (e.g., submitting product or store reviews). In order to provide you with the Services you request, BuyingIQ may require that you first provide certain personal information, which we determine is necessary in order for us to fulfill your request. If you indicate an interest in participating in a Service, we will identify what specific personal information you must provide prior to collecting such information. Any personal information which we collect from you will only be used for the purposes identified in this Privacy Policy, the BuyingIQ Terms of Use and any other applicable Member Agreement with BuyingIQ, and as may otherwise be indicated at the time the information is collected. To update, modify or delete any personal information you provide to us with respect to a Service you may access the Account section on BuyingIQ 

When you register on BuyingIQ, we collect and store your username, e-mail address and a password. While using some of the BuyingIQ Services, you may also choose to provide the following personal information: 

  1. Profile information, including first and last name, location, wishlist etc
  2. Product information, including the ratings, reviews, comments and other content you post
  3. Contact information, including email address, mailing address and phone number
  4. Other information that allows us to personalize your experience on the Website

The term "Submissions" refers to the information that you submit or post to BuyingIQ for public display, such as business ratings, reviews, photos, compliments, and the information that you display as part of your account profile. BuyingIQ may publicly display your submissions in order to provide the services that we offer. When we display your submissions, we do so along with your account name (first name and last initial or username). By using the personal information in your submissions (such as a photo of yourself), third parties may be able to identify you, associate you with your user account, and contact you. As such please do not include information in your submissions that you expect to keep private. You may reduce the risk of being personally identified by choosing a fictitious account name, though doing so could detract from the credibility of your submissions. 

We may store additional information about you in other ways not specifically described here. For example, if you contact us to provide feedback, register a complaint, or ask a question, we will record any personal information and other content that you provide in your communication so that we can effectively respond to your communication. 

BuyingIQ may collect its visitors; statistical information regarding what pages are visited, the date and time of the visits, how long it took a user to download a page, the TCP/IP address of the user etc. These automated server functions do not collect this information in a manner intended to identify your individual use of the Website, nor do we use this information for any such purpose. This information is collected to assist us in maintaining a high quality site, as well as, providing necessary traffic information to our advertisers. We may contract with other online partners to help manage and optimize our Internet business and communications. We may use third party website analytics services in connection with the Website to help us measure the effectiveness of our advertising and how visitors use our site. (See Cookies and Web Beacons) 

As a registered BuyingIQ user, you can modify some of your personal information and your privacy preferences by accessing the Account section of the Website. You can close your BuyingIQ account by contacting us using the Contact Us button on our homepage. We may retain some information from closed accounts so that we can comply with law, prevent fraud, assist with investigations, resolve disputes, analyze or troubleshoot programs, enforce our User Agreement and take other actions otherwise permitted by law. 

### INFORMATION FROM OTHER SOURCES

We may receive Personal Information about you from other sources like telephone, fax or email, from third-parties that provide services for us in connection with the Website or Services, as well as from other users and third parties to whom you may have voluntarily provided information. We may add this information to the information we have already collected from you via the Website or Services. This Privacy Policy does not restrict our use of that additional information. 

### EMAIL COMMUNICATIONS

At any time, you may opt out of receiving any promotional messages from BuyingIQ.com, but you may not opt out of administrative emails (for example, emails about your transactions or policy changes) while you are a member of BuyingIQ. Unregistered users (See Information from Other Sources) who receive e-mails from us may also opt-out of receiving further e-mails by following the instructions contained in our e-mails 

BuyingIQ does not tolerate spam. We do not sell or rent email addresses to any unauthorized third party. This does not mean that we can prevent spam from happening on the Internet. If you believe that you have received an unsolicited email from us, please let us know using the Contact Us button. 

### COOKIES AND WEB BEACONS

BuyingIQ.com and the third parties it authorizes may automatically receive and store certain types of non-personally identifying information, such as the computer;s IP address, type of operating system, type of internet browsing software, what web pages were viewed at what time, the geographic location of your internet service provider and demographic information (gender, age group), whenever you interact with us by using Cookies and analogous technology. Cookies are small files that are placed on your computer or your internet browser memory to enable the owner of the cookie to recognize your browser and to provide convenience and other features to you. So, for example, our cookies may allow us to show you the past products you have searched for on our Website. It is important to note that the cookies that we use, or permit others to use, do not contain and are not tied to any personally identifying information about you. 

BuyingIQ may permit certain third parties, including advertising networks and website analysis firms, to place cookies on your computer/browser when you visit our Website. These third party cookies are used to gather non-personally identifying information about your activities on our Website and third party websites to serve you with advertisements while you are on third party websites. These third parties do not know or have access to the name, address, email address, or any personally identifying information about BuyingIQ's users. 

You may be able to direct your internet browser not to allow cookies and you can typically delete existing cookies from your computer at any time. Please note, however, some elements of our Website will not function properly or be available to you. 

### TRANSFER OF INFORMATION

BuyingIQ.com may disclose your personal information to any third party in case: 

  1. it is required of BuyingIQ in order to provide you with a particular Service you have requested
  2. it is required of BuyingIQ in order to comply with a legal process in any applicable jurisdiction (e.g., court order, search warrant, law enforcement request etc);
  3. BuyingIQ determines, in its sole discretion, that disclosure is necessary to protect the rights, property, and safety of BuyingIQ, its subsidiaries, affiliates, co-brand partners or other parties under contract with BuyingIQ, our users, or others;
  4. it is required of BuyingIQ to share it with a prospective seller or actual seller of any business or assets BuyingIQ may acquire
  5. all or any of BuyingIQ;s assets are acquired by a third party

BuyingIQ may distribute your Submissions to third parties, as permitted pursuant to our Terms of Service. The third parties may in turn publicly display or publish your Submissions in connection with their own websites and media platforms. When we distribute your Submissions to third parties, we typically include your account name (but not your personal information unless you include your personal information in your Submissions). 

BuyingIQ may also share your personal information with its parent company, subsidiaries, joint ventures, or other companies under a common control (collectively, "Affiliates") that we may have now or in the future, in which case we will require them to honor this Privacy Policy. 

In certain instances, BuyingIQ may request that you provide secondary information (e.g., demographic information), which we may use, for example, to learn more about our customers and to develop and improve our services. Any requests for secondary information will be marked "optional" (or its equivalent). We may compile your personal information with that collected from other customers to create aggregate data. Aggregate data is information about groups of customers and, once compiled, will in no way identify you as an individual. We may disclose aggregate data to our Affiliates, advertisers, and other parties. 

### THIRD PARTY LINKS

BuyingIQ.com may contain links to websites of third parties. BuyingIQ is not responsible for the actions of these third parties, including their privacy practices and any content posted on their websites. We encourage you to review their privacy policies to learn more about what, why and how they collect and use your personal information. Except as set forth herein, we do not share your personal information with those third parties, and are not responsible for their privacy practices. 

### SECURITY

BuyingIQ.com uses industry standard measures to protect the personal information that is stored in our database. We restrict access to your personal information to employees that need to know that information in order to operate, develop or improve our services. However, third parties may unlawfully intercept or access transmissions or private communications. Therefore, although we work very hard to protect your privacy, we do not promise, and you should not expect, that your personal information or private communications will always remain private. 

If you have any questions about our Privacy Policy, please let us know using the Contact Us button on the homepage.
